<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UE5 on Baked Bits</title>
    <link>https://mcleary.github.io/tags/ue5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UE5 on Baked Bits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 20:33:32 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mcleary.github.io/tags/ue5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mesh to MetaHuman Gallery</title>
      <link>https://mcleary.github.io/posts/mesh-to-metahuman-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 20:33:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcleary.github.io/posts/mesh-to-metahuman-gallery/</guid>
      <description>Mesh to MetaHuman Gallery A collection of MetaHumans created using the new Mesh to MetaHuman tool in the new MetaHuman Plugin for Unreal Engine 5
Official Documentation  Mesh to MetaHuman Mesh to MetaHuman Quick Start       Press Coverage  fxGuide: Huge update for MetaHuman : Import your own head! AWN: Unreal Engine Mesh to MetaHuman Plugin Now Available 80.tv: Epic Games&#39; New Release Brings a Mesh to MetaHuman Feature to UE GameFromScratch: Make Your Own MetaHuman in Unreal Engine 5 CGPress: Epic updated Metahuman with ability to import custom character meshes  Twitter Turning Buddha into a #MetaHuman using the new MetaHuman plugin for Unreal Engine 5 #UnrealEngine5 #MeshToMetaHuman pic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Sponza UE5</title>
      <link>https://mcleary.github.io/posts/modern-sponza-ue5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 14:37:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcleary.github.io/posts/modern-sponza-ue5/</guid>
      <description>The Modern Sponza rendered in Unreal Engine 5 with Lumen The original Sponza scene is a classic in the field of computer graphics research. Originally created by Crytek for use in CRYENGINE for testing rendering features it was quickly adopted by the community making appearances in several academic papers and CG experiments. The original scene can still be downloading from the CRYENGINE Marketplace and, to this day, it is an amazing piece of graphics to look at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Unreal Engine Data Assets using only Blueprints</title>
      <link>https://mcleary.github.io/posts/unreal-data-assets-from-blueprints/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 12:09:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mcleary.github.io/posts/unreal-data-assets-from-blueprints/</guid>
      <description>In Unreal Engine&amp;rsquo;s terminology, a Data Asset is an asset that stores, guess what, data. It can be used, for example, to decouple the configuration from behaviour.
Data Assets in Unreal Engine all inherit from the UDataAsset. You can define a new Data Asset type by inheriting from UDataAsset and then your new data asset will become available in the Pick Data Asset Class Dialog:
I&amp;rsquo;m used to create new data assets using C++, you inherit from UDataAsset, add some members with UPROPERTY and done, however, recently I wanted to create one using only Blueprints.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
